solidsmack.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy and Policy - SolidSmack

## PRIVACY POLICY

_Effective: May 25, 2018_

EVD Media, LLC, its websites and subdomains (“us”, “we”, or “Company”), and we at SolidSmack, dearly respects your privacy and is committed to safeguarding your privacy while online at solidsmack.com. The following discloses how we gather and disseminate information for this site.

**What Information Do We Collect?**  
We request and/or process data from you when you visit and perform an action on our website. The following is the data we request and/or process for different actions you perform on the website.

When contacting us or subscribing to an email newsletter on our site, you may be asked to provide your:

  * Name
  * E-mail address

When ordering a product, additional information may include:

  * Billing/Shipping address
  * Credit card information

Other information that may automatically be captured when visiting our site or submitting a form include:

  * IP address
  * Country
  * Time of visit and/or time of form submission
  * Other data that could directly or indirectly identify you

**What Legal Basis Do We Have for Processing Your Data?**  
Processing of your personal data requires a legal basis. Processing of your data is only done when necessary to provide the relevant information for the stated purpose. These purposes include:

  * Providing communication via email about news published on the SolidSmack website
  * Providing information via email about products purchased through the SolidSmack website
  * Providing communication via email in the form of special offers and event promotion
  * Providing ongoing service and support

The most predominant legal bases for our processing of your personal data are:

  * When you provide consent
  * When we pursue legitimate interests
  * When we’ve entered into a contract with you
  * When we have a legal obligation or requirement

**RSS FEED AND EMAIL UPDATES**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to the RSS feed via email updates, we ask for contact information, such as name and email address. This is always an opt-in operation where you provide your email and name through a subscription option on the website. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email communication or by emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**LOGS, STATS, AND ANALYTICS**  
Like most websites, we use web-based analytics–specifically Google Analytics. This stores information such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, referring website, exit and visited pages, the platform used, date/time stamp, link clicks and gathers broad demographic information for aggregate use. Though this captures a lot of information, none is linked to personally identifiable data. and all user and event data is set to expire after 38 months.

**COOKIES**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. The SolidSmack website uses cookies to collect traffic data and traffic through the purchase process. No personal data is collected. This information is passed on to analytic reports and used to monitor site traffic and completed purchases.

We have implemented the following:

  * Remarketing with Analytics
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting
  * Facebook Pixel
  * Integrated services that require Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers

We, along with third-party vendors (such as Google), use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the Google advertising cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. It’s important to note that, while we do not use Google advertising, the website analytics data has the possibility of being used by them.

To clear your cookies, view these [instructions](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050?hl=en). You may also opt-out using this browser [add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**LINKS**  
This site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We suggest users be aware of this when they leave SolidSmack and read the privacy statements of each and every site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by SolidSmack.

**AFFILIATE DISCLOSURE**  
SolidSmack is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to [Amazon.com](https://amazon.com/?tag=solid0a-20). This means that SolidSmack may earn a commission when visitors purchase an item off of [Amazon.com](https://amazon.com/?tag=solid0a-20), after clicking a referral link from solidsmack.com.

**ADVERTISERS**  
SolidSmack does not use direct or third-party display advertising via banner ads. No outside company is used to display ads on this site and, therefore, there are no cookies to track your information and/or activity are set by outside advertising companies or platforms. We do publish sponsored content (aka advertorial, paid content, or native content) that may contain a link to an external site. With this, we may provide a tracking link to show where the click originated from. However, there is no personal data transmitted and we do not provide any personal data or access to any of the personal data of SolidSmack subscribers.

**Do We Transfer Personal Data Abroad?**  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. (an example of this is the service we use to send emails.) We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.

If you utilize our website from a country other than the country where SolidSmack is located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from a location outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

**Your Rights**  
You are at any time entitled to be informed of the personal data about you that we process, but with certain legislative exceptions. You also have the right to object to the collection and further processing of your personal data including profiling/automated decision-making. Furthermore, you have the right to have your personal data rectified, erased, or blocked. Moreover, you have the right to receive information about you that you have provided to us, and the right to have this information transmitted to another data controller (data portability).

**Deletion of Personal Data**  
You have the right to erasure. We will delete your personal data when we no longer need to process it in relation to one or more of the purposes set out above. Generally, we will store the most current data provided up to a period of 38 months after your last activity on the website.

However, the data may be processed and stored for a longer period in order to provide you information on orders and services, and/or for us to improve the services.

You may request your information be deleted by contacting [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4232302b3423213b02312d2e2b26312f2321296c212d2f) and we will delete the personal information it holds about you (unless we need to retain it for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy).

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, send an email notifying you of any changes, and/or update the privacy policy modification date herein.

**Terms and Conditions**  
Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at <https://www.solidsmack.com/terms/>.

**Contact and Complaints**  
If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA) and believe we maintain your personal data subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you may direct questions or complaints to your National Data Protection Authority (DPA):

If you wish to appeal against the processing of your personal data or if you have any questions regarding this privacy policy,  [Contact Us](https://www.solidsmack.com/contact/) or email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1565677c6374766c55667a797c71667874767e3b767a78).
